# **HIROKO BOUZAS**

# **UX/UI Designer, Web Developer**

UX/UI design professional with +10 years of experiences from full stack designer in IT startups to lead UX designer in a leading company.

I bring creative problem-solving approach and engineering logical perspective together to create simple but elegant products.

My overseas work experience has provided me deep empathy over culture differences, which fuels my passion to craft inclusive and intuitive experience for people.

# **Experience**

# Freelance Designer, Web Developer 2014 - Present

- · Design consultation, branding for small businesses, startups.
- · Project management, Art direction, scheduling, budget adjustment.
- UX/UI design for digital products, Graphic design, Illustration.
- · Web programing.

# Art Director, Lead UX Designer 2018 - Present

#### U-NEXT.Co.,Ltd. / Tokyo Japan

- Working on rebranding project with brand designers to increase the value of the company and impression of the service.
- Collaborating with CEO, stake holders to define the new brand identity that matches the company's business direction and customers satisfaction.
- Leading Implementation process of new brand identity to the multi-platform product such as iOS, Android, Android TV, fire TV, web, PlayStation.

# Chief Designer 2016 - 2018

#### Zweispace Japan / Tokyo Japan

- Responsible for all the design materials of the company, supervised design consistency across products.
- Comprehensive design work from defining user stories to final products, considering usability and development efficiency.
- Front-end web development.
- Managing SEO for web based products, web advertisements such as Google AdWords, Facebook Ads, affiliate marketing.

# Chief Designer, Front-end Developer 2015 - 2016

#### Nex-pro / Tokyo Japan, Yangon Myanmar

- · Responsible for all the design materials of the company.
- Educated design fundamental to Yangon's front-end development/design team through projects, managed and supervised them both in Yangon and Tokyo.
- · Front-end web development.
- Involved in web marketing projects using LP and web advertisements such as Google AdWords, Facebook Ads, affiliate marketing.

# Graphic Designer, UX/UI Designer 2013 - 2014

#### Studio SPEC / Sydney Australia

- DTP design to transform complex information in simple way.
- · Teaching small class of graphic design foundation course.
- UX/UI design for website, web application.

#### Graphic Designer 2008 - 2012

# **UCHINO Life Style Designing / Tokyo Japan**

- Delivering graphic design, product design, package design for big named brands such as Walt Disney Japan.
- · Learned principal idea of working as a team.





(+81) 70 4415 4956



http://hiroko.design/

# Language

Japanese Native English Fluent

French Conversational

#### **Work Condition**

Eligible to work within European Union

#### **Skills**

User Research, Experience strategy, Information Architecture, Wire-framing, Interface Design, Responsive Web Design, Graphic Design, Design Consultation, SEO Management, Web Marketing, HTML, CSS, SASS, LESS, JavaScript, Git.

# **Education**

# First Certificate in English (FCE)

Cambridge Examination / Sydney Australia 2013

Bachelor of Arts /

Visual Communication Design

Musashino Art University Tokyo Japan

2004-2008